Ifeanyi Umeh

Junior Electrical Engineer / Software Developer

Phone: 9059771116 **Address:** 255 fifth ave

Email: somto_umeh@yahoo.com

I am a Full Stack Web & Mobile Developer enthusiast, experienced in the entire software development lifecycle process, from project planning, UI/UX design, development, testing, deployment, and continuous maintenance. With an Electrical engineering degree

and fast learning ability, i am really confident that I would be a great asset to your company.

EXPERIENCE

Rudaina Foundation

May 2018 - March 2021

Full Stack Web & Mobile Developer

Architected With: HTML | SCSS | JavaScript | ReactJS | Redux | Firebase | Git | NodeJS | React Native | iOS | Android | etc To implement: Authentication, Admin panel, Event calendar system, real time chat, Social network, Q&A forum, Image/file upload, user roles, Lifestyle Tracker, etc

That resulted in:

A full stack web application that satisfied the business requirements. Some of which includes; Users can sign up, register for charity events, update profile, join groups chats, ask questions on forums, etc. Admins can post events, manage user registration, upload blogs, manage subscribers, etc

A full stack cross platform (iOs & Android) mobile app that satisfied the business requirements. Some of which includes; Users can track their diet, sleep, etc. View company news & blogs, Ask question and get replies in forums, etc Accomplishments:

I was presented an "Excellence award" in recognition for "Outstanding performance and team work" Project url: https://www.rudaina.org/

5k foam fest ottawaMay 2017 - August 2017

Associate

- Supervised adults and children in completing a long-distance race to raise money for charity.
- Assisted participants with various conflicts during the event.

Lacombe Rentals

May 2021 - August 2021

Maintenance Technician

- Using blueprints to construct porta potty based on their design schematics
- Testing and servicing porta pottys to ensure they have no issues when they are delivered

SKILLS

Front-End: CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, NextJS

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java,

Embedded systems: microcontrollers, ARM processors, FPGA board

Application tools: MATLAB, Linux environment, open-source components, Microsoft Word, Ms.Excel, Ms.powerpoint, Git & Github, AutoCAD, INTELLICAD, COSMOS

Electrical: Troubleshooting analog circuits using digital multimeters, function generators, oscilloscope, piezoresistive pressure sensor, Analyzing software design patterns

PROJECTS

FOURTH YEAR PROJECT

September 2020

- The current ravensim software was improved to accommodate the experimental analysis on Logisim
- Worked as a team to complete the project before the end of the winter semester
- JavaScript was useful for the front and back-end code development while Java was suitable for the GUI development
- Improvements were made to the menu bar, attributes table, I/O pins, components on the grid and multiple input

Remote Controlled Self-Watering Plant with Cellular Support/Control

September 2019

Languages and tools: Arduino board, Java, C++

- Acted as a team member, a user-controlled plant watering system was designed.
- Java and C++ programming was used to implement codes into the Arduino board through a computer which then enabled us to program the board to do things such as respond to calls and give the device commands when necessary.
- Such commands include, checking soil temperature or humidity through a cellphone and watering the plant remotely.

FPGA Alarm Clock with Customizable Sound

January 2019

Languages and tools: Vivado, C

• C programming was used to build an alarm clock on an FPGA board with the help of Vivado (software to implement C code that interacts with FPGA board)

Personalized Nuts and Crosses Game

March 2018

Languages and tools: Arduino Uno, Java, bluejay app

- Java was used to re-create the nuts and cross game on the bluejay app.
- · Sounds and images were used to bring life into the game

Reverse Engineering Project

October 2016

Languages and tools: AutoCAD, IntelliCAD, 3D printer, SolidWorks

- AutoCAD and IntelliCAD was used to design the reverse engineered water fountain straw.
- The 3D printer was used to bring the AutoCAD drawing to life.

Omnifood- Never cook again:

October 2021

https://e4anyi.netlify.app

Omnifood is an AI-powered food subscription that will make you eat healthy again, 365 days per year. It's tailored to your personal taste and nutritional needs.

Flexbox Challenge

August 2021

https://codepen.io/e4anyi/pen/ExmGOew?editors=1100

Used my learning of Flex box to implement a poster on CodePen

Monsters Roladex

November 2021

https://ifeanyiumeh.github.io/Monzters-Rolodex/ React Project with JSon

Crown clothing

https://crwn-fashion-clothing.herokuapp.com/

Architected With: HTML | SCSS | JavaScript | ReactJS | Redux | Firebase | Stripe | Node | Express | Git | NodeJS | NextJs | Progressive Web App | Heroku | etc

To implement: Modern E-commerce store UI/UX interface, Authentication, manage cart, make purchase, etc

EDUCATION

Carleton University

Sept 2016- May 2021

Bachelors of Engineering: Electrical Engineering

For my Final project, I worked with a team that used JavaScript to make improvements on the software such as making the menu bar, attributes table, I/O pins, components on the grid and multiple input configurations. which Received a grade A to all participants.

Zero To Mastery Coding Bootcamp

Online Education-Ongoing

I understand that this is a very fast paced field. So to ensure I am always learning and practicing my skills, I take courses on platforms such as Udacity, CodeAcademy, Udemy, etc. Check out

CERTIFICATIONS

Build Responsive Real-world Websites with HTML and CSS

Udemy

Learnt modern HTML5, CSS3 and web design by building a stunning website for your portfolio! Includes flexbox and CSS Grid

Git and GitHub: The practical guide on Udemy

Udemy

Learnt Git & GitHub and master working with commits, branches, the stash, cherry picking, rebasing, pull requests & more!

The Linux command line bootcamp: Beginner to power user

Udemy

Level Up Your Skills And Take Control Of Your Machine, w/ Dozens of Commands, Projects, and Challenges!

Workplace Hazardous Materials Information System (WHMIS)

Ontario

Compulsory certificate at first year of university